# Kibra Buluts

## Junior Full-Stack Software Engineer

Indianapolis, IN · kibra99@gmail.com · kibra-buluts.netlify.app · in/kibra-buluts · github.com/Kiibra

Full-Stack Software Engineer with a background in behavioral science with creativity and analytical skills with passion for innovation and problem-solving that drives me to develop user-centric software solutions that enhance the user experience.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

**Software:** JavaScript | React.js | HTML5 | CSS3 | JQuery | Python | PostgreSQL | Postman | Express.js | Node.js | ReactRouter | JWT | MongoDB | Mongoose | SASS | Bootstrap | Django | Docker | Styled-Components | Netlify | Trello | SQLite | MySQL | Slack | Whimsical | Zoom | Git | GitHub | Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint, etc.)

#### SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

March 2024 - Present

# Guess the Country of the Flag | App | Javascript, CSS3, HTML5

GitHub Link

- An educational trivia game app for fun and engaging learning experience through multiple-choice questions and challenges.
- MEN-stack CRUD application with Google OAuth authentication and authorization

## VeganRify | App | Node, Express, MongoDB, Google OAuth, Docker, Javascript, CSS, HTML5

GitHub Link

- Developed a web app using the MEN stack (MongoDB, Express, React.js, Node.js) that verifies if products are vegan, featuring full CRUD operations, tested with Postman, and a card generator using JavaScript, CSS3, and HTML5.
- Implemented OAuth 2.0 for secure user authentication, enabling signup, login, profile management, and product feedback.

#### Tech Haven | App | React.js, Express, Node.js, MongoDB, JWT Auth, Javascript, CSS, HTML5

GitHub Link

- A MERN stack web app that enables users to buy and sell used tech devices, ensuring seamless transactions and a high-quality user experience.
- Created the front-end with React.js, handling API data with JavaScript array methods, testing API routes with Postman, and managing Git for version control until deployment.

## Daily Diary | App | Django, Python, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, CSS, HTML5

GitHub Link

- Developed a Django personal diary app for securely managing daily entries.
- Built an MVP with Trello, wireframed with Whimsical, and used Python, Django, PostgreSQL, and HTML/CSS for full-stack CRUD operations.
- Implemented secure user authentication with Django's built-in system for user profile management.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# **General Assembly, Remote** — *Engineering Fellow*

March 2024 - Present

• Full-stack software engineering immersive student in an intensive, 12-week, 500+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies. Developed a portfolio of individual and group projects.

# Stepping Stones LLC, Registered Behavioral Technician

Indianapolis, IN

Sep 2023 - Mar 2024

- Recorded accurate and detailed data on client behaviors using data recording software and tools for behavioral analysis.
- Analyzed, interpreted, and utilized client data to track progress & outcomes.
- Communicated with clients, families, and supervisors to coordinate care, report progress, and modify treatment plans.

#### Mindful & Modern ABA, Registered Behavioral Technician

Indianapolis, IN

Dec 2022 - Sep 2023

- Adjusted strategies based on client needs, feedback from families, and supervisors.
- Followed structured treatment protocols and maintained consistency in client sessions.
- Engaged in ongoing training and certification to stay updated with best practices.

# Chipotle Mexican Grill, Crew Member

Westminster, MD

Aug 2020 - Aug 2021

- Worked in a team as a crew member/server with exceptional interpersonal skills.
- Consistently met and exceeded sales targets while providing amazing customer service.

#### **EDUCATION**

## **General Assembly** — *Remote*

Software Engineering Immersive – Expected Graduation: 06/202

• Completing 12-week, immersive coding bootcamp that involves creating 4 frontend, backend, and full stack applications in teams and independently

## McDaniel College — Westminster, Maryland

Bachelor of Arts, Psychology - August 2017 - May 2021